The story of life on Earth...
地球生命的故事……
...is marked by a series of
……以一系列……为标志
catastrophic extinction events.
灾难性灭绝事件。
Natural disasters which have threatened to wipe out
威胁要摧毁一切的自然灾害
many of the creatures that call our planet home.
许多以我们星球为家的生物。
But after every brush with death,
但每次与死神擦肩而过之后，
life has come back
生活又回来了。
even stronger.
甚至更强。
One of the most devastating catastrophes took place
其中一场最具破坏性的灾难发生了
66 million years ago,
6600万年前，
an asteroid hit the Earth
一颗小行星撞击了地球
with the destructive force of nine billion atomic bombs...
拥有相当于90亿颗原子弹的破坏力……
ending the reign of the giant dinosaurs.
终结了巨型恐龙的统治。
But it wasn’t the blast that wiped them out.
但真正将他们消灭的并不是爆炸。
It was the decade of darkness that followed.
接下来是长达十年的黑暗时期。
After the skies cleared,
天空放晴后，
the Earth would belong to a new dynasty of animals
地球将属于一个新的动物王朝。
we are a lot more familiar with.
我们对此更加熟悉。
Mammals.
哺乳动物。
66 million years ago
6600万年前
life on Earth is thriving.
地球上的生命正在蓬勃发展。
Polar forests cover the high arctic,
极地森林覆盖着北极高纬度地区。
Winter is over
冬天结束了
and months of total darkness have come to an end.
长达数月的完全黑暗终于结束了。
At last Spring is here.
春天终于来了。
Sunlight shines on this lost world
阳光照耀着这个失落的世界
where dinosaurs reign supreme.
恐龙称霸天下。
This Nanuqsaurus is enjoying the spring air.
这只纳努克龙正在享受春天的气息。
He’s a gigantic arctic predator,
他是北极的巨型掠食者，
weighing as much as three polar bears.
重量相当于三只北极熊。
An older male, he’s seen a lot of life.
他年纪较大，阅历丰富。
He still wears his white winter feathers.
他仍然披着白色的冬羽。
Good for camouflage in the snow,
适合在雪地里伪装。
but he sticks out a bit
但他有点显眼。
now that the trees are turning green.
现在树叶都变绿了。
Don’t let the peaceful forest fool you,
不要被宁静的森林所迷惑，
this guy knows another rival
这家伙认识另一个对手
could be hiding anywhere in here.
它可能藏在这里的任何地方。
A surprise encounter could result in a fight to the death.
突如其来的遭遇可能导致生死搏斗。
So, when he stumbles into a female’s nesting area,
所以，当他误入雌鸟的筑巢区域时，
he is wary.
他很谨慎。
But there’s nothing to worry about.
但没什么好担心的。
She is his mate.
她是他的伴侣。
They have been together for twelve years.
他们在一起已经十二年了。
And they’ve had each other’s backs
他们一直互相支持。
through many extreme Arctic seasons.
经历了北极许多极端寒冷的季节。
Springtime is a relief from the winter darkness,
春天是冬日黑暗后的曙光，
but the months of plenty are yet to come
但丰收的月份尚未到来。
when all the animals here can bask in a long hot summer
当这里所有的动物都能享受漫长炎热的夏天时
of 24 hour sun.
24小时不间断的阳光。
Life is starting to gear up.
生活节奏开始加快了。
Trees take leaf,
树木发芽，
warming waters tell these mayflies,
水温升高告诉这些蜉蝣：
that it’s time to hatch.
是时候孵化了。
Everywhere there is renewal.
处处都在复苏。
It’s the same for our Nanuqsaurus couple.
我们的纳努克龙夫妇也是如此。
She has just laid her eggs and they are getting
她刚下完蛋，蛋正在孵化。
ready to have a family.
准备组建家庭。
Our new mom has built a nest of leaves that
我们的新妈妈用树叶搭了个窝，
not only protects her eggs but also generates warmth
它不仅能保护卵，还能产生热量。
which helps them incubate.
这有助于它们孵化。
But a nice warm home like this has also
但像这样温馨舒适的家也有……
attracted a sleepy squatter.
吸引了一个昏昏欲睡的非法居住者。
This tiny mammal, an Unnuakomys, is napping the day away.
这只名叫乌努阿科米斯的小哺乳动物正在打盹儿。
But he’s not bothering anyone,
但他并没有打扰任何人。
so our couple doesn’t pay him any mind.
所以这对夫妇根本没把他放在眼里。
A strange animal call drifts up from the valley below.
山谷下方飘来一阵奇怪的动物叫声。
Mom finishes covering her eggs.
妈妈盖好了鸡蛋。
Now it’s time to hunt.
现在是狩猎的时候了。
The pair work well together,
他们俩合作得很好。
they’ve done this many times before.
他们以前多次这样做过。
Edmontosaurus.
埃德蒙顿龙。
A vast herd of these herbivores have arrived from the south
一大群这样的食草动物从南方迁徙而来。
in search of plants to graze.
寻找可供放牧的植物。
But these beasts won’t be easy prey for our Nanuqsaurus couple.
但对于我们的纳努克龙夫妇来说，这些野兽可不是容易对付的猎物。
An adult Edmontosaurus is as long as a school bus,
成年埃德蒙顿龙的体长和一辆校车一样长。
far too large even for our two predators.
即使对于我们这里的两种捕食者来说，体型也太大了。
But they have a plan...
但他们早有计划……
and wait for their moment.
静待时机。
Right on time some teenagers arrive.
几个青少年准时到达。
And like most teenagers they are impatient.
和大多数青少年一样，他们缺乏耐心。
What they don’t realize is they have bigger problems
他们没有意识到，他们面临着更大的问题。
than who gets to eat first.
比谁先吃更重要。
What looks like a dim star,
看起来像一颗昏暗的星星，
is actually an asteroid.
它实际上是一颗小行星。
Seven and a half-miles wide,
宽七英里半，
hurtling towards the Earth at 45,000 miles per hour.
以每小时 45,000 英里的速度向地球疾驰而来。
For the dinosaurs this is the end of the world.
对恐龙来说，这就是世界末日。
66 million years ago
6600万年前
the climate is warm, and many species of
气候温暖，适宜多种生物生存。
plant and animal life thrive even at the poles.
即使在两极，动植物也能繁衍生息。
The dinosaurs rule the world
恐龙统治世界
for now.
目前。
They have no idea everything is about to change.
他们丝毫没有意识到一切即将改变。
4,500 miles to the south
向南4500英里
a giant asteroid has slammed into the Earth,
一颗巨型小行星撞击了地球。
unleashing the destructive force
释放破坏力
of nine billion atomic bombs.
九十亿颗原子弹。
Landing off the coast of what is now Mexico.
在如今的墨西哥海岸附近登陆。
The rock penetrates deep into the Earth’s crust,
岩石深入地壳，
which triggers mega tsunamis at sea.
这会引发海上超级海啸。
And releases a blast that incinerates everything
然后释放出一股爆炸力，将一切都焚毁殆尽。
on land within 1,000 miles.
在方圆 1000 英里内的陆地上。
But far away in the Arctic Circle
但远在北极圈内
devastation has yet to hit.
灾难尚未真正降临。
And though their world is about to end, the dinosaur predators
尽管它们的世界即将终结，但恐龙捕食者
continue to hunt as they have done for millions of years.
它们会像数百万年来那样继续狩猎。
The adolescent group have identified their target,
青少年团体已经确定了他们的目标群体，
a young Edmontosaurus with his mother
一只幼年埃德蒙顿龙和它的母亲
on the edge of the herd.
在兽群边缘。
The eager teenagers go on the attack,
这些跃跃欲试的青少年发动了进攻，
while our couple wait.
这对夫妇在等待。
At the same time, shockwaves from the blast
与此同时，爆炸产生的冲击波
are racing across the planet at close to the speed of sound
正以接近音速的速度横跨地球
...minutes after the asteroid hit.
小行星撞击地球几分钟后。
The first shock waves reach the Nanuqsaurus Arctic home.
第一波冲击波抵达了纳努克龙的北极家园。
Triggering earthquakes and blind panic among the dinosaurs.
引发地震，并在恐龙中造成盲目恐慌。
The herd stampedes.
牛群奔腾而过。
In the chaos those that can’t keep up are trampled.
混乱之中，跟不上节奏的人会被践踏。
Finally, the tremors stop.
最终，震动停止了。
One of the teenagers didn’t survive.
其中一名青少年不幸身亡。
But his pals spot a chance to pick up where they left off...
但他的伙伴们发现了一个机会，可以继续他们未完成的工作……
...a juvenile, abandoned by the herd.
……一只被牛群遗弃的幼牛。
He doesn’t stand a chance.
他毫无胜算。
Our Nanuqsaurus couple watch...
我们的纳努克萨鲁斯夫妇正在观看……
and now they make their move.
现在他们开始行动了。
After letting the teenagers do the hard work,
在让青少年们完成艰苦的工作之后，
our more experienced team steals the prize.
我们经验更丰富的团队最终赢得了比赛。
They’ve been running this con for years.
他们这个骗局已经持续好几年了。
Mom and dad claim the kill.
爸爸妈妈都声称猎物是她打的。
Hours have passed since the asteroid slammed into Earth.
小行星撞击地球至今已过去数小时。
But now another wave is tearing through the atmosphere.
但现在另一股浪潮正席卷大气层。
An intense air blast.
一股强烈的气流。
It overtakes the old couple.
它超过了那对老夫妇。
But they battle on to get back to their nest.
但它们会奋力游回巢穴。
At last, the winds break.
风终于停了。
In all their years together,
在他们共同生活的那些年里，
they’ve never experienced anything like this.
他们从未经历过这样的事情。
Despite the chaos most creatures try to carry on as normal.
尽管一片混乱，大多数生物还是试图像往常一样生活。
This young Nanuqsaurus may not know what happened,
这只幼年纳努克龙可能不知道发生了什么事。
but he isn’t going to let a good Edmontosaurus carcass
但他不会放过一具保存完好的埃德蒙顿龙尸体。
go to waste.
浪费掉。
He’s interrupted by a little opportunist.
他被一个小投机分子打断了。
A Dromaeosaur.
驰龙。
He has also brought a friend.
他还带来了一位朋友。
And another.
还有一个。
But this is no family style restaurant.
但这并非一家家庭式餐厅。
The Nanuqsaurus is not going to let these
纳努克龙不会让这些
scavengers interrupt his dinner.
食腐动物打断了他的晚餐。
Further up the valley our couple finally approach home.
沿着山谷继续向上走，这对夫妇终于接近了家。
They don’t know the high winds have damaged their nest,
它们并不知道强风已经损坏了它们的巢穴。
exposing their hidden eggs.
揭露它们藏匿的卵。
Making them easy picking for a band of Dromaeosaurs.
这使得它们很容易成为一群驰龙的猎物。
They’ve returned seconds too late.
他们回来晚了几秒钟。
Even the father’s terrifying show of strength
甚至父亲那令人胆寒的力量展示也令人震惊。
can’t save their babies.
救不了他们的孩子。
The mother finds four of her eggs were destroyed.
母亲发现自己的四个蛋被毁了。
Heartbroken, they console each other.
他们心碎不已，互相安慰。
A terrifying and deadly day for all the Artic animals.
对于北极所有动物来说，这是可怕而致命的一天。
They might hope that tomorrow will be easier.
他们或许会希望明天会更容易些。
But the asteroid isn’t finished with them yet.
但小行星还没放过他们。
In fact, the worst is yet to come.
事实上，最糟糕的情况尚未到来。
A towering pillar of pulverized rock dust
一根高耸的碎岩粉柱
rises from the impact crater.
从撞击坑中升起。
Dense and vast it starts to blocks out the sun
它浓密而广袤，开始遮蔽阳光。
for the entire planet.
为了整个地球。
A time of endless darkness has arrived and threatens
无尽的黑暗时代已经来临，并带来威胁。
all life on Earth.
地球上所有生命。
An asteroid has hit the Earth
一颗小行星撞击了地球
launching billions of tones of debris into the atmosphere.
向大气层排放数十亿吨碎片。
A dark cloud starting to covering the entire planet.
一团乌云开始笼罩整个地球。
This black swirling dust, rich in carbon and sulfur,
这种富含碳和硫的黑色旋涡状尘埃，
is about to make the world uninhabitable
即将使世界变得不适宜居住
for millions of creatures.
对于数百万生物而言。
Almost five thousand miles north of the impact,
撞击点以北近五千英里处
the creatures of the Arctic are about to face
北极的生物即将面临
the asteroid’s final blow.
小行星的最后一击。
As the debris cloud reaches them.
当碎片云到达他们面前时。
They are plunged into total darkness.
他们陷入了彻底的黑暗。
They will never see the sun again.
他们将再也见不到阳光了。
Even animals who are adapted to dark Arctic winters
即使是那些适应了北极漫长冬季的动物
will find this darkness unlike anything
你会发现这种黑暗与任何事物都截然不同。
they’ve experienced before.
他们以前有过类似的经历。
Earth, once home to a diverse spectrum of colorful life,
地球，曾经是丰富多彩的生命家园，
is transforming into a dark mass of gray.
正在变成一团暗灰色的东西。
Two months later what should be a hot summer
两个月后，本应是炎热的夏天。
is instead a deep freeze.
而是一个深度冷冻室。
The natural rhythm of life is being turned upside down.
生命的自然节奏正在被彻底颠覆。
For our Nanuqsaurus couple, there is more tragedy.
对于我们的纳努克萨鲁斯夫妇来说，还有更多悲剧。
Their remaining eggs have frozen in the bitter cold.
它们剩下的蛋都在严寒中冻住了。
Even this brave mother couldn’t protect them
即使是这位勇敢的母亲也无法保护他们。
from the decay and death of a world with no sunlight.
从一个没有阳光的世界的衰败和死亡中。
With no reason to stay by the nest they share,
没有理由继续留在他们共同的巢穴里，
the two decide to move on.
两人决定继续前进。
As months pass,
几个月过去了，
trillions of tons of dust strangle the planet.
万亿吨尘埃笼罩着地球。
Rain is scarce.
降雨稀少。
And what does fall is turned to acid.
而掉落的物质都会变成酸。
In this cold darkness, plants can no longer produce
在这寒冷的黑暗中，植物无法再生长。
their energy through photosynthesis.
它们通过光合作用获取能量。
Even mature trees are dying.
就连成熟的树木也在死亡。
It’s the beginning of the end for plant eaters
这是食草动物末日的开始。
who will starve.
谁会挨饿？
This young Edmontosaurus
这只年轻的埃德蒙顿龙
is struggling to breathe.
呼吸困难。
Dust has filled his lungs.
灰尘充满了他的肺。
But even worse, he’s lost his herd.
但更糟糕的是，他失去了他的牛群。
He would be easy prey for our resting pair of Nanuqsaurus.
对于正在休息的那对纳努克龙来说，他简直就是唾手可得的猎物。
Fortunately for him, with so many dying
对他来说幸运的是，当时有那么多人死去
herbivores around,
周围有食草动物，
they’ve already eaten.
他们已经吃过了。
The youngster is spared.
这名年轻人幸免于难。
The Edmontosaurus herd is following their
埃德蒙顿龙群正跟随它们的
instincts and heading south.
出于本能，一路向南。
Their senses tell them it’s winter.
他们的感官告诉他们，现在是冬天。
They have no idea there’s nothing
他们根本不知道什么都没有。
for them to the south but more cold and darkness.
对他们来说，南方将更加寒冷和黑暗。
For the Nanuqsaurus, the departure of the Edmontosaurus
对于纳努克龙来说，埃德蒙顿龙的离开
herd means scarcity and hunger will hit the predators too.
畜群意味着食物匮乏，饥饿也会影响到捕食者。
Life is about to become desperate for our old pair.
我们这对老兄的生活即将变得岌岌可危。
It’s been more than a year since the asteroid
小行星撞击地球至今已超过一年。
collided with Earth and the planet is an alien world.
它与地球相撞，而这颗星球是一个外星世界。
It remains shrouded in a thick cloud of foul dust.
它仍然笼罩在一层厚厚的污浊尘埃中。
And this apocalyptic, endless night,
而这末日般的、无尽的黑夜，
the average temperature has dropped 36 degrees
平均气温下降了36度
and the once thriving ecosystems have frozen to death.
曾经繁荣的生态系统已经冻死了。
The Arctic, like much of the planet,
北极，就像地球上的大部分地区一样，
is in an unprecedented deep freeze.
正处于前所未有的严寒之中。
Incredibly, there are places water still runs.
令人难以置信的是，有些地方仍然有水流淌。
And here, near the Nanuqsaurus’ old nesting site, is an oasis.
在纳努克龙的旧巢穴附近，有一片绿洲。
An area of volcanic activity has caused the ground to warm.
火山活动导致地表升温。
Water is now flowing here instead of ice.
这里现在流动的是水而不是冰。
And that attracts life.
这样就能吸引生命。
Insects thrive in the water.
昆虫在水中繁衍生息。
They provide food for the birds.
它们为鸟类提供食物。
Miraculously, the dark gray world is still showing signs of
奇迹般地，这片灰暗的世界仍然展现出一些迹象。
life and hope for the future,
生命和对未来的希望，
at least for these smaller creatures.
至少对于这些体型较小的生物来说是这样。
Our brave Nanuqsaurus pair
我们勇敢的纳努克龙夫妇
are still hanging on, unsure what their future holds.
他们仍在苦苦支撑，对未来感到迷茫。
Our mother is once again carrying eggs.
我们的母羊又怀孕了。
But something is wrong and she is growing sicker by the day.
但是情况不对劲，她的病情一天比一天严重。
It will be impossible for her to bring life into this world.
她不可能将生命带到这个世界上。
Her mate is powerless to help.
她的伴侣无力帮助她。
Unbearably, in order for him to find food,
令人难以忍受的是，为了找到食物，
he must leave her on her own.
他必须把她独自留下。
With no choice, he ventures into the unknown,
别无选择之下，他冒险进入了未知领域。
leaving her without his protection.
他让她失去了保护。
She is now alone and vulnerable.
她现在孤身一人，处境脆弱。
The two teenage Nanuqsaurus are back.
两只青少年纳努克龙回来了。
Hungry and impatient as usual.
像往常一样又饿又没耐心。
They haven’t eaten for days and are desperate.
他们已经好几天没吃东西了，非常饥饿。
Once, they saw her as competition...
曾经，他们视她为竞争对手……
...now, she is prey.
现在，她成了猎物。
She will not go without a fight,
她不会束手就擒。
but the end is inevitable.
但结局是不可避免的。
The forests are frozen.
森林都结冰了。
And almost all large land animals are dead and gone.
几乎所有大型陆地动物都已经灭绝了。
Without sunlight, the web of life that
如果没有阳光，生命之网就会崩溃。
supported them has collapsed.
支撑他们的那部分已经崩溃了。
Only the bones of our female Nanuqsaurus remain.
只剩下我们发现的雌性纳努克龙的骨骼了。
Sitting beside her skeleton is her devoted mate.
坐在她骸骨旁边的是她忠诚的伴侣。
Now alone, he must endure the cold and conserve his energy
如今他孤身一人，必须忍受寒冷，保存体力。
and hope for something, anything,
并抱有一丝希望，哪怕是任何希望。
to give him a chance to survive.
给他一个活下去的机会。
Year two of endless night on Earth.
地球上的第二个无尽黑夜。
It is a catastrophe for all life,
这对所有生命来说都是一场灾难。
especially large animals like the dinosaurs.
尤其是像恐龙这样的大型动物。
Our old female Nanuqsaurus put up a fight,
我们那只年老的雌性纳努克龙奋力反抗，
but is long gone.
但早已不复存在。
Miraculously, her mate is still alive.
奇迹般地，她的伴侣还活着。
Enduring the cold and scavenging for food.
忍受严寒，四处觅食。
His body has even become a refuge
他的身体甚至成了避难所
for other living creatures.
对于其他生物而言。
In his feathers,
在他的羽毛里，
the tiny mammal, Unnuakomys, picks ticks from his skin.
这种体型娇小的哺乳动物，学名 Unnuakomys，会从皮肤上挑出蜱虫。
A good exchange for the warm bed.
用温暖的床换取一张好床。
The Nanuqsaurus never did shed his winter coat.
纳努克龙始终没有脱掉它的冬毛。
At last, he spots what he has been waiting for.
他终于看到了自己一直在等待的东西。
One of the adolescent Nanuqsaurus
其中一只幼年纳努克龙
is wasting his energy chasing birds.
他把精力浪费在追逐鸟类上了。
Still, our male waits.
然而，我们的男主角仍在等待。
He watches as the kid wears himself out.
他看着那孩子把自己累得筋疲力尽。
Then, he summons what little
然后，他召唤出仅有的那一点点东西。
strength he has for the attack.
他拥有进攻所需的力量。
Revenge is sweet.
复仇的滋味真甜。
Our Nanuqsaurus is now the last of his kind.
我们的纳努克龙现在是同类中最后一只了。
After a 170 million year reign,
经过1.7亿年的统治，
the giant dinosaurs are passing into history.
巨型恐龙正在成为历史。
Years go by, and still,
岁月流逝，依然如此。
the dark cloud blankets the Earth.
乌云笼罩着大地。
Robbed of the sun’s energy, three quarters of
失去了太阳能量，四分之三的
all species across the planet are driven to extinction.
地球上所有物种都走向灭绝。
Finally, a decade later...
最终，十年之后……
the dust clouds clear and give way to a new dawn.
尘埃落定，黎明到来。
Seeds that have laid dormant in the soil spring to life.
土壤中休眠的种子苏醒过来。
Few animals made it,
只有少数动物幸存下来。
finding creative ways to survive.
寻找创造性的生存方法。
Some hid underground...
有些人躲藏在地下……
...some in water.
……有些在水中。
But all were small and adaptable.
但它们都很小巧，适应性强。
The planet they inherited is a blank canvas,
他们继承的星球就像一张空白的画布。
and evolution is about to go into overdrive.
进化即将进入超速运转阶段。
Five million years later
五百万年后
a vibrant new habitat now dominates the land.
如今，一片充满活力的全新栖息地占据了这片土地。
Lush, tropical rainforests.
郁郁葱葱的热带雨林。
Beneath the canopy, the air is filled with the scent
树冠下，空气中弥漫着香气。
of colorful flowers
五彩缤纷的花朵
and the hum of pollinating insects.
还有授粉昆虫的嗡嗡声。
The only descendants of the dinosaurs that have
恐龙的唯一后代
survived are the birds.
幸存下来的是鸟类。
Other creatures have made the most of this new
其他生物已经充分利用了这一新特性。
environment and found ways to thrive.
环境并找到了生存之道。
High in the canopy, it is not just the birds
在高高的树冠上，不仅仅是鸟类。
looking for breakfast.
想找个地方吃早餐。
These are Plesiadapis.
这些是近齿鲎。
They are mammals, and mammals are thriving
它们是哺乳动物，而哺乳动物正在繁荣发展。
in these new forests.
在这些新形成的森林里。
This is a fruit hunting mission.
这是一次寻找水果的任务。
They work together to find the best afternoon snack.
他们一起合作，寻找最好的下午茶点。
And there are plenty of delicious options.
而且还有很多美味的选择。
The new world is so abundant,
新世界如此富饶，
they have the luxury to choose only the ripe ones.
他们有条件只挑选成熟的果实。
Plesiadapis is one of the very first primates.
近猴是最早的灵长类动物之一。
A group of mammals whose intelligence and climbing skills
一群智力和攀爬能力都很强的哺乳动物
have helped them seize the high ground up in the tree canopies.
帮助他们占据了树冠上的高地。
But in the water below, there is danger.
但下面的水中却暗藏危险。
Not every reptilian predator...
并非所有爬行动物捕食者……
died with the dinosaurs.
与恐龙一同灭绝。
It is five million years after the asteroid impact.
距小行星撞击事件已过去五百万年。
The world is now covered in lush tropical rainforests.
如今，世界各地都被郁郁葱葱的热带雨林覆盖。
Here, birds and mammals thrive.
这里是鸟类和哺乳动物繁衍生息的地方。
The giant dinosaurs are gone,
巨型恐龙已经消失了，
but other reptilian predators have survived.
但其他爬行动物捕食者却幸存了下来。
This Plesiadapis is safe
这种拟态生物是安全的。
as long as he stays in the trees.
只要他待在树上。
But this tasty snack is just out of reach
但这种美味的零食却遥不可及。
and he makes a potentially fatal mistake.
他犯了一个可能致命的错误。
This little mammal has no idea
这只小哺乳动物完全不知道
what lurks in the murky depths.
幽暗深处潜藏着什么？
It doesn’t look good for our little...
情况对我们的小家伙不太妙……
aw, never mind.
哦，没事了。
Crocodiles survived the apocalyptic winter
鳄鱼在末日般的寒冬中幸存了下来
because they lived in the water and could go long periods
因为它们生活在水中，可以长时间待在水里。
without eating.
不吃东西。
After devouring his prey, this giant Kosmodraco
吞食猎物后，这只巨大的科斯莫德拉科
likes to take a long bask in the sun.
喜欢长时间晒太阳。
He settles down and opens his mouth wide to keep cool.
他平静下来，张大嘴巴降温。
But a nice warm patch of sand attracts all sorts
但是，一片温暖舒适的沙滩会吸引各种各样的生物。
of creatures from the forest...
来自森林的生物……
...like Titanoides.
……比如钛铁矿。
Mammals like these have evolved to be immense
像这样的哺乳动物已经进化得体型巨大。
and powerful.
而且威力强大。
Large enough to take on the biggest reptiles.
体型大到足以与最大的爬行动物搏斗。
These tough guys now rule the shores.
这些硬汉现在统治着这片海岸。
The age of the mammals has truly arrived.
哺乳动物的时代已经真正来临。
No longer in the shadow of the reptiles,
不再生活在爬行动物的阴影下，
mammals will soon dominate the planet.
哺乳动物很快将主宰地球。
When scientists became convinced that
当科学家们确信
a cosmic collision killed off the dinosaurs,
一次宇宙碰撞导致恐龙灭绝。
it inspired more thorough scientific study
它激发了更深入的科学研究。
of the threat asteroids present to life on Earth.
小行星对地球生命构成的威胁。
Starting in the 1990s,
从上世纪90年代开始，
astronomers all over the world have been using
世界各地的天文学家一直在使用
their telescopes to track and catalog
他们利用望远镜进行跟踪和编目
the many objects flying around our Solar System.
围绕我们太阳系飞行的众多天体。
Today, they believe they have found all asteroids
如今，他们认为已经找到了所有的小行星。
large enough to cause a similar mass extinction event.
规模大到足以引发类似的物种大灭绝事件。
And while none of these present
虽然这些人都不在场
any immediate danger, there are thousands of
如无迫在眉睫的危险，有成千上万的人可以依靠。
smaller objects which could cause major destruction
较小的物体也可能造成重大破坏
if they impacted the Earth.
如果它们撞击了地球。
Recently, a 100-foot-wide lump of rock
最近，一块宽100英尺的巨石
called 2024-YR4 was spotted
名为 2024-YR4 的探测器被发现
on a near-collision course with Earth.
正朝着地球近乎相撞的方向运行。
It will miss us, but only by luck.
它不会来，但只是侥幸。
Few scientists believe that watching the skies
很少有科学家相信观察天空
and hoping for the best is a winning strategy.
抱有最好的希望是一种制胜策略。
So, in 2021, NASA launched DART,
因此，在2021年，NASA发射了DART探测器。
a prototype of a new planetary defense system,
一种新型行星防御系统的原型
its aim was to smash into the side of an asteroid
它的目标是撞击一颗小行星的侧面。
and prove threats like these could be neutralized,
并证明此类威胁可以被消除。
if we spotted them in time.
如果我们及时发现它们的话。
The mission succeeded.
任务成功。
While some human technology may
虽然某些人类技术可能
pose a threat to life on Earth...
对地球上的生命构成威胁……
breakthroughs like the DART program could be what
像DART项目这样的突破性进展可能正是我们所需要的。
saves many species,
拯救了许多物种，
including our own,
包括我们自己的
from going the way of the dinosaurs.
避免重蹈恐龙灭绝的覆辙。
<i>♪ I see trees of green ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我看见绿色的树木 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Red roses too ♪</i>
<i>♪也是红玫瑰♪</i>
<i>♪ I watch them bloom ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我看着它们绽放♪</i>
<i>♪ For me and you ♪</i>
<i>♪ 为你和我 ♪</i>
<i>♪ And I think to myself ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我心想 ♪</i>
<i>♪ What a wonderful world ♪</i>
<i>♪多么美好的世界♪</i>
<i>♪ Yes, I think to myself ♪</i>
<i>♪ 是的，我心想 ♪</i>
<i>♪ What a wonderful world ♪</i>
<i>♪多么美好的世界♪</i>